virginiamason.org 2019-03-08

# Privacy Policy - Virginia Mason, Seattle, WA

### Notice of Privacy Practices - Downloadable and Translation Materials

  * English
  * Korean 
  * Russian
  * Spanish

The staff of Virginia Mason Medical Center respects the privacy of our patients and of our website users. If you don't find your concern addressed here, feel free to contact us by email or phone.

Privacy Policy Guiding Principles

  * Any information that you submit to us through our website - whether through a survey, registration form or email - will be used exclusively by Virginia Mason or third parties performing services for Virginia Mason.
  * We will use your personally identifiable information only for the specific reason for which you submitted it, (i.e., registering for a class).
  * We will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information including encryption with SSL technology and passwords when appropriate.
  * You will generally only receive email only for information that you have requested or as confirmation of information that you submitted (i.e., class registration).

Virginia Mason will use overall demographic data of our Web users to improve the site and enhance services. These demographic trends will not be traceable to an individual's personal information. On rare occasions, Virginia Mason may contact registered users by email to inquire about interest in potential new Web services.

### Privacy Policy

#### Information Collection and Use

Virginia Mason is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement, except to vendors and agents in support of Virginia Mason's activities. Virginia Mason does not commercially sell any customer lists or email addresses. Company may, however, disclose personal information if permitted or required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on Virginia Mason; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Virginia Mason, the website, or the users; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Virginia Mason, the website, or the public.

#### Registration

In order to use some parts of the Virginia Mason website, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information, usually your name and email address. This information is primarily used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest (such as access to clinical publications). It is optional for the user to provide demographic data (such as specialty), but encouraged, so we can provide you with better information when using our site.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information while visiting the Virginia Mason site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, he or she may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site (i.e., cannot view certain content). Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to further develop our website. Virginia Mason does not use Cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a Cookie. We may use non-personally identifiable information transferred through Cookies for promotional or marketing purposes.

#### Collection of Anonymous Information

In addition to the use of personal information, Virginia Mason may also gather anonymous information which may be used by Virginia Mason or shared with third parties. Generally this information is collected through "traffic data" and may entail the use of Cookies and IP addresses. Virginia Mason uses such traffic data to help determine how our users use parts of the website so we can analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use a better experience for you. IP addresses and other traffic data are not linked to personally identifiable information.

#### Links

This Website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Virginia Mason is not responsible for the privacy practices of these websites. Virginia Mason is not responsible for content provided on these sites or for the validity of content on these site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

#### Security Policy

We exercise care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Personal information collected by the Virginia Mason website is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. In many instances, such as in the case of credit card numbers and all on-line purchases, the personal information is encrypted before you conduct your transaction. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access, each having signed confidentiality agreements. Any employee who violates our privacy and/or security policies is subject to disciplinary action, including possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

#### Assignment

Virginia Mason may change its ownership or corporate organization while providing the website and services. As a result, please be aware that Virginia Mason may transfer your information to another company that is affiliated with Virginia Mason or with which Virginia Mason has merged. Any new company will also follow this Privacy Policy.

#### Your Acceptance of These Terms

By using this site, you signify your acceptance of the Virginia Mason Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our website. Your continued use of the Virginia Mason website following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

#### Notification of Changes

If Virginia Mason decides to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use our website for notice of changes to the Privacy Policy.

#### Correcting and Updating Information

Virginia Mason also permits you to correct or update personally identifiable information that you have previously provided to us. To do so, send email to: [emailvm@virginiamason.org](mailto:emailvm@virginiamason.org) indicating the information that you wish to be corrected or updated.

#### Opt-Out Procedures

You always may opt-out of receiving future contacts or mailings. Virginia Mason provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving electronic communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about you. To remove your personally identifiable information from our database, to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service, send email to [emailvm@virginiamason.org](mailto:emailvm@virginiamason.org) with the word "remove" in the subject line.

#### Questions

Questions regarding this statement should be emailed to [emailvm@virginiamason.org](mailto:emailvm@virginiamason.org).
